<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ENSIME | Ikenna Okpala]]></title>
  <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/categories/ensime/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-24T22:18:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ikennaokpala.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ikenna Okpala]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ikennaokpala.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emacs (starter-kit and emacs for Mac OSX), Scala and Ensime Configuration steps ]]></title>
    <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/emacs-scala-and-ensime-configuration-steps"/>
    <updated>2011-03-18T11:36:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/emacs-scala-and-ensime-configuration-steps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>(Before starting with this i think you may want to delete the~/.emac, ~/.emacs.d or ~/.emacs~ files from you computer, if they already exit. this is just my view.. reason being that the settings in the .emacs file.. i noticed overshadowed the settings in the emacs start-kit version.)</em></p>

<p>NB: Note that, this is <a href="https://github.com/kengimel/emacs-dotfiles">my cloned copy</a> and is specific to my system and user name.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>This post aims to guide you through the steps and get you setup based on <a href="https://github.com/kengimel/emacs-dotfiles">my cloned copy</a>.</p>

<p>To get cracking with this, type the following on the terminal: clone this git repo with the following:
<div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>git clone git@github.com:kengimel/emacs-dotfiles.git .emacs.d
ln -s .emacs.d emacs.d
cd emacs.d</code></pre>
</div>

next rename ikenna.el to your username on a mac that will be you shortname: the command below will give you the current username</p>

<p><div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>whoami    # this will return to tell you your current username
 mv kengimel.el yourusername.el</code></pre>
</div>

next rename kengimel.el to you system name, this can be gotten by typing:
<div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>hostname                # this will return to tell you your current hostname / system name
 mv ikenna.el yourhostname.el</code></pre>
</div>

Sometimes the hostname may appear verbose use this command to rename it, if you rename it don't to repeat the step above:</p>

<p><div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>scutil --set HostName yournewhostname</code></pre>
</div>

NB: you have to restart your machine for this to take effect</p>

<p>Next:
<div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>git submodule init
 git submodule update</code></pre>
</div>
</p>

<p>The commands above will update the ensime submodule for the project:</p>

<p>Next download and install <a href="http://emacsformacosx.com/">emacs for Mac OSX</a>.
<div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>cd vendor/ENSIME
 sbt update               # this may take a little while to come through
 sbt dist
 Stop existing ENSIME server by killing inferior-ensime-server buffer
 Restart ENSIME with M-x ensime
 M-x ensime-sbt #gives you ensime sbt goodness
 M-x eshell #gives you the already embedded command line terminal</code></pre>
</div>

Next open Applications folder and click Emacs.app to start emacs for Mac (You may notice that ensime will throw an error, don't worry just carry out the next steps below)</p>

<p>C-x C-f (control-x and control-f) and open the file with you system name Locate this line (i guess this will be around line number 151) (add-to-list 'load-path (concat dotfiles-dir "/vendor/ENSIME/elisp")) and edit it to this (add-to-list 'load-path (concat dotfiles-dir "/vendor/ENSIME/dist/elisp"))</p>

<p>DOWNLOAD SETUP THE FOLLOWING EMACS MODES:
<a href="http://www.thaiopensource.com/download/">NXML-MODE</a>
<a href="http://cx4a.org/software/auto-complete/#Downloads">AUTO-COMPLETE MODE</a></p>

<p>I advice to first try out your installation by debugging it with this command;
<div>
  <pre><code class='bash'>emacs --debug-init</code></pre>
</div>
</p>

<p>And now you ready to start writing some wonderful concise scala code with the help of emacs ENSIME. kudos to the guys behind the emacs starter kit, <a href="https://github.com/technomancy">technomancy</a>, <a href="https://github.com/g-eorge/">george agnelli</a>, <a href="https://github.com/topfunky"> topfunky</a> and <a href="https://github.com/aemoncannon/">aemon cannon</a>.</p>

<p>ROCK ON !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
