<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Out Of The Box (&quot;The Very Beginning&quot;) | Ikenna Okpala]]></title>
  <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/categories/out-of-the-box-the-very-beginning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-03T17:30:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ikennaokpala.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ikenna Okpala]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@ikennaokpala.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SCRIBE’S HIERARCHY – ORDER OF THE SCRIBES]]></title>
    <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/scribee28099s-hierarchy-e28093-order-of-the-scribes"/>
    <updated>2008-02-15T14:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/scribee28099s-hierarchy-e28093-order-of-the-scribes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LEVEL 1 - SCRIBBLER
The scribbler is the person who shows evident interest and aptitude for computer related hardware or software. It is their desired of concentration.</p>

<p>LEVEL 2 - SCRIBE-TECH
The Scribe Tech is actively working in the field and has an evident appetite for knowledge, through being a perpetual student. They tend to me more comfortable with computer software and hardware than people. The Scribe Tech is learning fast (but not learned) and does not have much to teach. They are however on their way to becoming an authority in the field.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>LEVEL 3 - JUNIOR SCRIBE
The Junior Scribe is an authority in either software or hardware, but has not gone beyond a limited number of skills. In other words, they might be a C++ expert, but uncomfortable in assembly language. They might be a renowned networking architect but know nothing about VoIP. The Junior Scribe needs only release their self imposed boundaries of knowledge and realize the infiniteness of their gift. The Junior Scribe has almost become a god (lowercase god), in their own right.</p>

<p>LEVEL 4 - SCRIBE (FULL-BIRD)
The Scribe has become manifested in the field of computer related technologies or their discipline (such as chemistry, physics, math, etc). When referring to someone outside of the computer related technology field as a Scribe, it is meant as a gesture of honoring the person though they are not directly in the Order of the Scribes. There is no limit to what they can accomplish in software or hardware. Their knowledge is achieved in no less than ten years in the discipline, but often longer. They don’t care much about anything other than other Scribes and their discipline. Though the Scribe may have never used a certain technology, they are already experts on it. These are the hacker’s hacker, the one’s slicing the bleeding edge. They are always ready to teach those READY to learn!</p>

<p>LEVEL 5 - SENIOR SCRIBE
The primary trait of the Senior Scribe is the ability to see the Scribe potential in others and the ability to train them to become Full Birds. They also often have attained purity, adaptivity, and maturity in methodological processes. These are the leaders of the Order of the Scribes.</p>

<p>LEVEL 6 - CHIEF SCRIBE
The Protector and Keeper of the Order of the Scribes. This position is similar to the Pope in that it is usually only passed on to another at death.</p>

<p>By</p>

<p>Barney A Taylor (Chief Scribe), PhD, founder of <a href="http://www.thirteenscribes.com/">Thirteen Scribes Inc.</a>,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When is the future?]]></title>
    <link href="http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/when-is-the-future"/>
    <updated>2006-04-14T14:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://ikennaokpala.com/blog/when-is-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my early years, I conceived the future as a distant state along the dimension of time waiting to happen; but as I grew up I got to learn that such a view of the future is not only naive, but ironically, unrealistic. Even though the literary perception of futuristic concepts suggests the above, it is flayed in the fact that it is practically unreal.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The future is now. Today was the future of yesterday. This moment was the future a nanosecond ago. This view has helped me gain some control of my life's direction based on the underlying principle of cause and effect. Since this realization, I have treated every futuristic phenonemon from the perspective of the network of causes, events, reactions and effects.</p>

<p>By Roland Ukor</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
